<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blake Merryman</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/</link><description>Recent content on Blake Merryman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.blakemerryman.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nashville Favorites</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/nashville-favorites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/nashville-favorites/</guid><description>Living in California during the pandemic definitely has me missing home. I thought it would be helpful to put together a list of my favorite spots back in Music City.</description></item><item><title>Swift Tips Series</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2017-11-09-swift-tips-series/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2017-11-09-swift-tips-series/</guid><description>Recently, I wrote a series of Swift tips over at my company’s blog. This started out as a simple CocoaHeads talk where I was sharing my own personal best practices with the group.
Striving for Smallness Documentation Organization Access Control Early Exits Closure-Based CollectionType APIs Property Configuration Lazy Sequences Debugging Slow Build Times I’d love to hear your thoughts and feedback. Feel free to reach out to me on Twitter @blakemerryman.</description></item><item><title>Bear Writer</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2017-10-19-bear-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2017-10-19-bear-notes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve lamented about my love/hate relationship with Evernote but I never followed up about my solution to this problem. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve given up on my dream of a custom built solution in favor of Bear, a simple yet beautiful note taking solution. It even checks off many of the boxes from my wish list:
Powered by plain text. Preview/rendering options. Multi-media support. Hand writing / drawing support. Customizable organization (via tags).</description></item><item><title>Evernote Alternative?</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-09-24-evernote-alternative/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-09-24-evernote-alternative/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long time Evernote user. With few exceptions, I dump everything that I think or discover into my Evernote database. I&amp;rsquo;ve even been a premium member until recently.
And yet, I&amp;rsquo;ve never loved Evernote. I feel like we have always been at odds. Things never work quite how I want them to and a lot of minor details leave me frustrated. I&amp;rsquo;ll save that rant for another post but the bottom line is this: I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a new note taking system for a long time and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been forced come back to Evernote because it is the lesser of many evils.</description></item><item><title>Initial Thoughts - Apple Special Event, Sept. 9, 2015</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-09-09-apple-special-event-sept-9-2015/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-09-09-apple-special-event-sept-9-2015/</guid><description>We all knew what was coming and it was still a doozy. The rumor mill basically got everything correct and this was still one of the best keynotes in a long time. I plan on writing more in depth about each major topic but for now, here are my first impressions.
Lack of “Status Updates”
In the past, Apple has kicked off every event with a stacatto of numbers about how great Apple has been doing.</description></item><item><title>Swift Scripts at CocoaHeads</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-02-16-cocoaheads-swift-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-02-16-cocoaheads-swift-scripts/</guid><description>Speaking of Swift, I delivered a presentation on scripting with Swift at Nashville CocoaHeads at the end of January, earlier this year. Check out the video and head over to the Github repository for the source code and more information.</description></item><item><title>Swift 1.2</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-02-13-swift-1.2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 12:31:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-02-13-swift-1.2/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about the changes to Swift in the current Xcode 6.3 beta. Apple has answered several of my biggest gripes with Swift. Here are some of the highlights:
Incremental builds for increased build performance Native Set collection class that bridges to NSSet, joining Array/NSArray and Dictionary/NSDictionary static methods and properties support for classes Improved type inference for single-expression closures Swift enums can now be exported to Objective-C let constants no longer need immediate initialization General performance enhancements General improvements to Swift-Objective-C interoperability And my personal favorite:</description></item><item><title>Youtube View Counter</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2014-12-23-youtube-view-counter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 16:52:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2014-12-23-youtube-view-counter/</guid><description>Youtube recently ran into issues with it&amp;rsquo;s view counter for the Gangnum Style video. Basically, Google was using 32-bit integers to store the view counter value for its videos. This means that it had a maximum possible value of 2,147,483,647. This essentially &amp;ldquo;broke the internet&amp;rdquo; (at least for this one video) when the number of views passed that limit. My friend Allen asked me why Google didn&amp;rsquo;t already use the 64-bit version (which has a maximum value of 9,223,372,036,854,775,807&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s nine quintillion with a Q) rather than 32-bit version.</description></item></channel></rss>