<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>writing on Blake Merryman</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in writing on Blake Merryman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.blakemerryman.com/tags/writing/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bear Writer</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2017-10-19-bear-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2017-10-19-bear-notes/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href="http://blakemerryman.com/2015/09/24/evernote-alternative/">lamented&lt;/a> about my love/hate relationship with Evernote but I never followed up about my solution to this problem. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve given up on my dream of a custom built solution in favor of &lt;a href="http://www.bear-writer.com">Bear&lt;/a>, a simple yet beautiful note taking solution. It even checks off many of the boxes from my wish list:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Powered by plain text.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Preview/rendering options.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Multi-media support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Hand writing / drawing support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Customizable organization (via tags).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Search.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Mobile friendly. There is apps for iPhone, iPad, &amp;amp; Mac.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Affordable and viable. Subscription pricing: $1.49/monthly or $14.99/annually.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Still missing from my wishlist:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Varied storage options. For now, iCloud is the only supported storage option. This is fine for now as I live in an Apple dominated world.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Text transcription. I can sketch and write on notes but can&amp;rsquo;t easily search this hand-crafted content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Web service. There is no way to access this content from the web.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Customizable templates. There is not any template support.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Extensible. There is no way to extend bear with your own functionality.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The silver lining in all of this is that I ostensibly control the content and it is being stored in an easily transferable format. This app is also well maintained and will hopefully add many of the features that I&amp;rsquo;m looking for.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Evernote Alternative?</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-09-24-evernote-alternative/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2015-09-24-evernote-alternative/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long time &lt;a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote&lt;/a> user. With few exceptions, I dump everything that I think or discover into my Evernote database. I&amp;rsquo;ve even been a premium member until recently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, I&amp;rsquo;ve never &lt;em>loved&lt;/em> Evernote. I feel like we have always been at odds. Things never work quite how I want them to and a lot of minor details leave me frustrated. I&amp;rsquo;ll save that rant for another post but the bottom line is this: I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a new note taking system for a long time and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been forced come back to Evernote because it is the lesser of many evils.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With all of the discussion about the &amp;ldquo;open web&amp;rdquo; lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with the idea of building my own system, using existing technologies and supplementing with my own open-sourced utilities. This post won&amp;rsquo;t go into the nitty-gritty details and is more of an outline of what features I think this system should have in order to meet my needs. So let&amp;rsquo;s begin.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wish-list">Wish List&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This list is not all encompassing, nor are all items required. These are just things I want (and use in my current system).&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Powered by plain text files. Whether you prefer to take notes in &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown&lt;/a>, HTML, plain text, or &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX">LaTex&lt;/a>, this system should take any and all text files without regard for the contents.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preview/rendering options. This system should easily allow the user to preview their marked-up plain-text content. Preferably with a live preview option. Also, presentation mode!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Varied storage options. A user should not have their thoughts and ideas locked into a third party&amp;rsquo;s cloud. They should be able to pick and choose and easily relocate their data at anytime. Ideally, the user can even host their own data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports multi-media. As much as the developer in me wishes that everything existed in text, even I have to add images &amp;amp; videos to my notes every now and again. This should be easy &amp;amp; intuitive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hand writing support. Some people just prefer to take notes the old fashioned way or have sketches interspersed throughout.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customizable organization. If the user wants to file things away in folders by month or year, great. If the user wants to file everything away in one large, hot-mess of a folder, also great.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Search. It should be easy to find what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Text transcription. This is one feature that Evernote really nailed and probably the hardest to replicate. Ideally, this would tie in with search as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile friendly (first?). We live in a progressively mobile first world whether we like it or not. This system should function equally well on phones, tablets, computers, and the web.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web Service. This system should be able to live on the web, including self-hosted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Affordable but viable. Fairly priced for consumers and the developer(s).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customizable templates. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re bookmarking sites or journalling, a good template can save you time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extensible. Feature missing? Easily add it in yourself.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Basically what I want is a fast, simple, powerful note taking platform that is also useful for bookmarking, planning, todo-list managing, and cross-platforming utility. Not much&amp;hellip; just everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will probably (read: definitely) be on long, drawn out process as I piecemeal this all together (or give up and move on to something else, as I’m want to do on projects like these).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have suggestions or thoughts, feel free to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/blakemerryman">contact me on Twitter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>