<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mom on Blake Merryman</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/tags/mom/</link><description>Recent content in mom on Blake Merryman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.blakemerryman.com/tags/mom/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Mother's Day Tray</title><link>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the pandemic, I picked up wood working as a fun hobby. This is something that I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for a long time; the act of creating a physical thing is very compelling to someone who works with intangible bits every day. The social distancing and isolation offered an opportunity to finally dive in head first. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a steady stream of projects over the past several months but today I want to share what I made my mother for Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Awhile back, I asked my mom what she&amp;rsquo;d like for her special holiday. She requested a nice large tray. Apparently trays are all the rage in decorative world these days (she&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an interior decorator). She didn&amp;rsquo;t give me much to work with but it was clear she didn&amp;rsquo;t want anything loud or overly trendy. My mom enjoys simple designs and clean lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to keep things simple and focus on the fit and finish of the tray. The design I came up with was straightforward: a miter box frame with a dado groove for the bottom panel. I spent several Saturdays in my garage milling, cutting, and recutting the parts. It took some work to get the miters just right. Then I sanded through the following grits: 80, 120, 220. I applied two coats of wipe on polyurethane to finish, sanding between and buffing afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wood was reclaimed from a couple of nice ladies on Craigslist. I believe it&amp;rsquo;s cherry or something similar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t take any pictures during the construction process so here is the final result:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/tray_hero.jpeg" alt="Tray hero shot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/tray_angle.jpeg" alt="A view of the tray from a dramatic angle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/tray_top.jpeg" alt="A top down view of a tray">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/tray_empty.jpeg" alt="An empty tray">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.blakemerryman.com/posts/2020-mothers-day/tray_wrapped.jpeg" alt="A gift-wrapped gray">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>